NICOLA ZANON

Front-End Developer, SEO & Web Designer.

.01 CONTACTS

www.nicola-zanon.com
(+44) 077 488 870 22
nicola.zanon86@gmail.com
SE14 6GJ

02 ABOUT ME

I am an italian web designer who decided to move to the UK to get a chance of working with the best people in the web industry.

STRENGHIS

High attention to details.

Fast learner and problem solver.

CAREER HISTORY

Time Inc.

(03/2016 - Current)

Lead Digital Developer

Responsable for devloping Rich Media ad formats, bespoke interactive websites and team management.

- Maintain and develop bespoke publishing platform
- Develop and integrate Front-end Automations
- Manage, mentor and be resposnable for the other developers in the team
- Optimise websites and digital campaigns performance
- Increase team efficency

Ignite Hospitality Marketing

(09/2014 - 10/2015)

Front-end Developer (Head of Team)

Responsable for developing mobile-first Wordpress powered website and improving team efficiency.

- Front-End Development
- Wordpress
- UX
- Performance Optimisation
- SEO
- Managing Tasks

Photobox Ltd

(03/2014 - 09/2014)

Developer (Integration team)

Responsable for developing and integrating new features on their Custom E-commerce platform.

- Front-End Development
- Responsive HTML email development
- Perl, Mason

Full Stack Freelancer

(2010 - Present)

Wordpress Developer - SEO

Working as a freelance on several projects, including web design, front-end development and devising SEO strategies based around specific keywords

- Designing Responsive web sites for several clients
- Writing cross-browser HTML5, CSS & Javascript
- Developing usable and clean Website that have a consistent look and feel throughout all web properties
- Working on budget restrictions
- Coding semantic web sites with strong focus on SEO factors

- SEO

Web design teacher

(2012 - Present)

Teacher

Teaching privately to different students the principles of graphics, web design and the Adobe suite:

- Web Development
- Graphic design
- Adobe suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign)

CAREER STATEMENT

I feel my greatest strengths are firstly my several different experiences on web related projects where I've learnt to work on various aspects of the matter.

Secondly my skill on developing mobile-first responsive web sites.

Thirdly my real passion for the Web as a whole, something that allows me to spot trends and develop best practice processes.

KEY SKILLS

- HTML5, CSS3, JS/jQuery, SASS/LESS, PHP, Performance Optimisation, WP
- Deep knowledge of Responsive web design process and related issues
- Awareness of the Web Development industry and new technology
- Knowledge of front-end developmnet and cross browser compatibility issue
- Can manage multiple projects in a fast-paced, deadline-driven environment
- Confident, friendly and easy to get along with.

AREA OF EXPERTIES

- Responsive Web Design
- Front-end development
- Graphic design
- Prototyping
- Search Engine Optimiza-
- T.T 1- --- 1-
- Web marketing

Strategies

- Analytic and reporting Troubleshooting

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Creative thinker
- Team player
- Hard worker
- Attention to detail
- Reliable
- Analytical
- Problem solving

SOFTWARE & TOOLS

- Wordpress
- Gulp/Grunt
- GIT
- MAMP, Vagrant
- Analytic tools
- Sketch
- Adobe Suite
- Google AdWords
- Excel

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

Milan Business School "Sole24 ore" (2012)

Professional training course in Web Marketing and new technology for communication.

Padua University (2005 - 2010)

Master of Arts in Social Psychology and organizations.